const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"The portal vein is formed by the union of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"The inferior mesenteric vein and the splenic vein","bool":false},{"option":"The superior mesenteric vein and the inferior mesenteric vein","bool":false},{"option":"The superior mesenteric vein and the splenic vein","bool":true},{"option":"The splenic vein and the inferior pancreaticoduodenal vein","bool":false},{"option":"The inferior mesenteric vein and the inferior pancreaticoduodenal vein","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following arteries provide the blood supply to the abdominal esophagus?","answers":[{"option":"Thoracic aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior thyroid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Suprarenal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left gastric artery","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"What is the rate-limiting enzyme of the urea cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Arginosuccinate lyase","bool":false},{"option":"Ornithine synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Carbamoyl phosphate synthetase","bool":true},{"option":"Arginosuccinate synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Ornithine transcarbamylase","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which statement is incorrect about gallbladder histology?","answers":[{"option":"Nerves and blood vessels in submucosa","bool":true},{"option":"Thin smooth muscle oriented diagonally","bool":false},{"option":"No muscularis mucosa and submucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelium with folds","bool":false},{"option":"Perimuscular dense connective tissue","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"During swallowing, respiration is inhibited for a fraction of the respiratory cycle. Which stage is this?","answers":[{"option":"Pharyngeal voluntary phase","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal phase","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal involuntary phase","bool":false},{"option":"Voluntary phase","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal phase","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following artery supplies blood to the pancreas?","answers":[{"option":"Left gastric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior esophageal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior mesenteric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Splenic artery","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following enzymes is responsible for cleaving off glucose-1-phosphate from the peripheral end of a long branch of glycogen during glycogenolysis?","answers":[{"option":"Branching enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Debranching enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen phosphorylase","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is true regarding bile canaliculi?","answers":[{"option":"They are found in the gall bladder","bool":false},{"option":"They only contain unconjugated bilirubin","bool":false},{"option":"They arise from the intercellular spaces between hepatocytes","bool":true},{"option":"They are the largest branches of the biliary tree","bool":false},{"option":"They empty into bile ductules","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"What are the permanent folds in the wall of the intestines, containing a core of submucosa called?","answers":[{"option":"Plicae","bool":true},{"option":"Crypts","bool":false},{"option":"Villi","bool":false},{"option":"Rugae","bool":false},{"option":"Pits","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following correctly describes the glycemic index?","answers":[{"option":"The ability of the liver to maintain blood glucose levels","bool":false},{"option":"The ability of food to increase blood glucose levels","bool":true},{"option":"The ability of the liver to increase blood glucose levels","bool":false},{"option":"The ability of the liver to reduce blood glucose levels","bool":false},{"option":"The ability of food to reduce blood glucose levels","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the rate-limiting enzyme in cholesterol synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Mevalonate carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Prenyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Squalene synthase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG-CoA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG-CoA reductase","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following cells are not present in the small intestine?","answers":[{"option":"Paneth cells","bool":false},{"option":"Absorptive cells","bool":false},{"option":"Microfold cells","bool":false},{"option":"Kupffer cells","bool":true},{"option":"Goblet cells","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"By which process do bile salts get absorbed in the terminal ileum?","answers":[{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Active transport","bool":true},{"option":"By binding with calbindin protein","bool":false},{"option":"Simple diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Osmosis","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Zymogen granules from pancreatic acinar cells are released by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Secretin","bool":false},{"option":"Ghrelin","bool":false},{"option":"Cholecystokinin","bool":true},{"option":"Glucose-dependant insulinotropic peptide (GIP)","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrin","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A 58-year-old male is diagnosed with diabetes. On multiple follow-up visits, his blood sugar levels are high despite reviewing his medication and ruling out any other causes for it. Upon detailed inquiry, the patient revealed that he takes his medication occasionally as he visits a faith healer who he believes will cure him and thinks daily medication is unnecessary. Which of the following should be the next step of management in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Admit him to the medical unit","bool":false},{"option":"Advise him to bring a family member on his next visit","bool":false},{"option":"Advise him to exercise daily","bool":false},{"option":"Make a diet plan for him to follow","bool":false},{"option":"Counsel him, keeping in mind the health belief model","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A distant relative comes to you for advice regarding her son. After listening to her, you conclude that her son might have schizophrenia. You recommend that she should visit a psychiatrist, to which she shows hesitation, stating that she cannot do that for it will bring disgrace to the family and people will make fun of them. Which of the following terms best defines the association of mental disorders with the fear of disgrace?","answers":[{"option":"Stigma","bool":true},{"option":"Pessimism","bool":false},{"option":"Discrimination","bool":false},{"option":"Disempowerment","bool":false},{"option":"Prejudice","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Children raised with this parenting style can depend on their caregivers, show distress when separated, and joy when reunited. They tend to seek comfort and reassurance from their caregivers. Which parenting style is being referred to here?","answers":[{"option":"Secure attachment style","bool":true},{"option":"Disorganized attachment style","bool":false},{"option":"Ambivalent attachment style","bool":false},{"option":"Permissive attachment style","bool":false},{"option":"Avoidant attachment style","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A high-resolution transducer is used in the transluminal sonography of the gastrointestinal tract. For the esophagus, how many layers can normally be visualized?","answers":[{"option":"6 concentric layers","bool":false},{"option":"5 concentric layers","bool":true},{"option":"2 concentric layers","bool":false},{"option":"3 concentric layers","bool":false},{"option":"4 concentric layers","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A 45-year-old presents with a 1-week history of swelling in his right inguinal region, which appears on exertion and disappears on lying down. For the past 1 day, the swelling became painful and has since not gone away. On examination, it is now tense and tender. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Strangulated hernia","bool":true},{"option":"Direct inguinal hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructed hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Incarcerated hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect inguinal hernia","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Ascites secondary to an increase in hydrostatic pressure solely occur in which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Cirrhosis","bool":true},{"option":"Neoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Constructive pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Infection","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"When is the primary prophylaxis in spontaneous bacterial peritonitis indicated?","answers":[{"option":"Bilirubin < 2.5 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"Ascites fluid protein > 1.5 g/l","bool":false},{"option":"Creatine > 1.2 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"Serum Na > 130 mg/l","bool":false},{"option":"Child pugh score > 9","bool":true}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the odd one out regarding Meckel's diverticulum?","answers":[{"option":"It is present in 2% of the population","bool":false},{"option":"It can function as ectopic pancreatic tissue","bool":false},{"option":"It forms on mesenteric side","bool":true},{"option":"It is due to a persistent vitelline duct","bool":false},{"option":"It is also called ileal diverticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A person presents to the emergency department with chronic diarrhea and abdominal pain for months. Findings show aphthous ulcers, deep linear fissures occupying the ascending and transverse colon but sparing the rectum and descending colon with skipped areas with excess fat creeping over mucosa. Cryptitis is also seen in lamina propria along with non-caseating granulomas. Which is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Celiac disease","bool":false},{"option":"Ulcerative colitis","bool":false},{"option":"Whipple disease","bool":false},{"option":"Crohn's disease","bool":true},{"option":"Lactose intolerance","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is due to the failure of the return of the physiological herniation of the gut in the yolk sac back into the abdominal cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Omphalocele","bool":true},{"option":"Retrocolic hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Megacolon","bool":false},{"option":"Persistence of vitelline duct","bool":false},{"option":"Gastroschisis","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the region having villi and submucosal glands?","answers":[{"option":"Duodenum","bool":true},{"option":"Jejunum","bool":false},{"option":"Large intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Ileum","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"During a colonoscopy, the colon is examined for the cause of blood in the stool. Which of the following is not a characteristic feature of the structure observed?","answers":[{"option":"Crypts of Lieberkuhn","bool":false},{"option":"Glands in the mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Few villi","bool":true},{"option":"Teniae coli","bool":false},{"option":"Numerous goblet cells","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is not a tributary of the portal vein?","answers":[{"option":"Left gastric vein","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic vein","bool":true},{"option":"Superior pancreaticoduodenal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superior mesenteric vein","bool":false},{"option":"Splenic vein","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Filtered blood exits the liver via which of the following vessels/structures?","answers":[{"option":"Cystic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic vein","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatic portal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic artery","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following abdominal viscera is most vulnerable to trauma to 9-11 ribs on the left side of the body?","answers":[{"option":"Gall bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Appendix","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"The pancreas is considered a retroperitoneal organ. Which part of this gland is intraperitoneal?","answers":[{"option":"Head","bool":false},{"option":"Uncinate process","bool":false},{"option":"Neck","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":false},{"option":"Tail","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A number of structures open (related) in the 2nd part of the duodenum. Which of the following does not have an opening in the duodenum?","answers":[{"option":"Ampulla of Vater","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreatic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic duct","bool":true},{"option":"Bile duct","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory pancreatic duct","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A second-year resident in surgery, while revising the anterior abdominal wall, noticed that the conjoint tendon resists the occurrence of an inguinal hernia. The tendon that resists the hernia is made of aponeurotic fibers from which of the following muscles?","answers":[{"option":"External oblique and internal oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Internal oblique and transversus abdominis","bool":true},{"option":"External oblique and transversus abdominis","bool":false},{"option":"Internal oblique and rectus abdominis","bool":false},{"option":"External oblique and rectus abdominis","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"The second-year MBBS students studying stomach specimens noted lesser curvature. Incisura angularis represents the junction between which of the following anatomical locations?","answers":[{"option":"Cardia and fundus","bool":false},{"option":"Cardia and pyloric part of stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Body and pyloric part of stomach","bool":true},{"option":"Fundus and pyloric part of stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Cardia and body","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A patient with chronic epigastric pain comes for a follow-up with a computed tomography scan report of the abdomen showing enlarged gastric nodes. Which of the following structures drains into it?","answers":[{"option":"Superior 2/3rd of stomach","bool":true},{"option":"Right 2/3rd of inferior 1/3rd of stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Pylorus of stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Middle part of esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Left 1/3rd of greater curvature","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A demonstrator while explaining lymphatic drainage of the stomach, tells students the relation of lymph nodes with the arteries. Which of the following lymph nodes are located along the short gastric and left gastro-omental arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Pyloric","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior gastric","bool":false},{"option":"Superior gastric","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreatico-duodenal","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreatico-splenic","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A patient, after the caesarian section, comes into the outpatient department with a complaint of a bulge in the midline of the anterior abdominal wall. After examination and investigation, a diagnosis of the separation of\r\nrectus abdominis due to weakened linea alba is made. Separated muscle is innervated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"T5 to T12","bool":true},{"option":"T3 to T7","bool":false},{"option":"T2 to T7","bool":false},{"option":"T3 to T11","bool":false},{"option":"T1 to T5","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A house officer, while examining a child, notices that the stroking of skin on the medial aspect of the thigh results in reflex contraction and retraction of the testis. Which of the following muscles of the anterior abdominal wall is responsible for this reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Rectus abdominis","bool":false},{"option":"Transversus abdominis","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidalis","bool":false},{"option":"External oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Cremaster","bool":true}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"The reflected inguinal ligament receives fibers from the contralateral aponeurosis of which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Transverse abdominal oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus abdominis","bool":false},{"option":"External abdominal oblique","bool":true},{"option":"Internal abdominal oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidalis","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A 60-year-old male presents in the surgical outpatient department with a complaint of swelling in his left groin. After examination, a diagnosis of a direct inguinal hernia is made. Which of the following fossae are potential sites for direct inguinal hernias?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral inguinal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Medial inguinal fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Supravesical fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Iliac fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Ischiorectal fossa","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A 60-year-old alcoholic male comes to the medical outpatient department with dilated veins in his abdominal region. He is diagnosed with caput medusae due to portal hypertension. Which of the following veins, when dilated, produces caput medusae?","answers":[{"option":"Para-umbilical vein","bool":true},{"option":"Splenic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreatic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Proper hepatic vein","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"How are pelvic splanchnic nerves distinct from other splanchnic nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Derived from ventral primary rami of L2, L3, L4","bool":false},{"option":"Provide postganglionic sympathetic innervation to the cecum","bool":false},{"option":"Convey preganglionic parasympathetic fibers to the inferior hypogastric plexus","bool":true},{"option":"Derived from the sympathetic trunks","bool":false},{"option":"Convey postganglionic parasympathetic innervation to the ascending colon","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"In which of the following structures, hypertrophic pancreatic tissue can be seen?","answers":[{"option":"Anal canal","bool":false},{"option":"Jejunum","bool":false},{"option":"Rectum","bool":false},{"option":"Mouth","bool":false},{"option":"Meckel's diverticulum","bool":true}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A histological section is being observed showing a serous gland of compound tubulo-acinar variety. The secretory unit consists of pyramidal serous cells and specialized pale, low cuboidal epithelial cells. Numerous spherical cell clusters are also scattered. Which of the following structures is being observed?","answers":[{"option":"Submandibular","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":true},{"option":"Sublingual","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenum","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Choose the correct option regarding the derivative of hepatic bud.","answers":[{"option":"Hepatic sinusoids","bool":false},{"option":"Hemopoietic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Stroma of liver","bool":false},{"option":"Kupffer cells","bool":false},{"option":"Parenchyma of liver","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Select the incorrect option regarding derivatives of dorsal pancreatic bud.","answers":[{"option":"Entire main pancreatic duct","bool":true},{"option":"Head (upper part)","bool":false},{"option":"Tail","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":false},{"option":"Neck","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A newborn's failure to pass meconium within the first 24 hours after birth may indicate which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Intestinal malrotation","bool":false},{"option":"Tracheoesophageal fistula","bool":false},{"option":"Hirschsprung disease","bool":true},{"option":"Esophageal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal atresia","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A 1-day-old newborn with a history of bilious vomiting. The baby's physical examination is normal. There is a history of polyhydramnios during pregnancy. An abdominal X-ray shows a double bubble gas shadow. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Midgut volvulus","bool":false},{"option":"Pyloric stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal atresia","bool":true},{"option":"Imperforate anus","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal atresia","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A neonate presents with persistent vomiting and respiratory distress. A trachea-esophageal fistula (TEF) is suspected. What is the most common type of this fistula?","answers":[{"option":"Esophageal atresia with a proximal TEF","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal atresia with double TEF","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal atresia with distal TEF","bool":true},{"option":"Pure esophageal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Isolated TEF","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following effects is produced in the gastrointestinal tract by the stimulation of the parasympathetic nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in absorption of nutrients","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of secretion from the stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of intestinal secretions","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of sphincters","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in motility and tone","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Secretion of gastrin hormone is increased by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Low pH of gastric juice","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoactive intestinal peptide (VIP)","bool":false},{"option":"Somatostatin","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric inhibitory peptide (GIP)","bool":false},{"option":"Products of protein digestion","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following mechanisms causes maximum gastric acid secretion?","answers":[{"option":"H2 receptor stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Neurogenic stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Cholinergic receptor stimulation","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of acetylcholine release","bool":false},{"option":"Na/K ATPase pump stimulation","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following inhibits gastric acid secretion by action on the parietal cell?","answers":[{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrin","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandin E","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Hepcidin prevents the absorption of which of the following substances from the small intestine, thus preventing its accumulation in the blood?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Folate","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Copper","bool":false},{"option":"Iron","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"The monosaccharide fructose is absorbed into the intestinal epithelial cells with the help of which of the following transport proteins?","answers":[{"option":"GLUT4","bool":false},{"option":"SGLT1","bool":false},{"option":"SGLT2","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT5","bool":true},{"option":"GLUT2","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which type of electrical and motor activity in the gastrointestinal tract occurs during periods of fasting?","answers":[{"option":"Migratory motility complex","bool":true},{"option":"Segmentation","bool":false},{"option":"Peristalsis","bool":false},{"option":"Slow wave complex","bool":false},{"option":"Basic electrical rhythm","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is a biochemical reaction that occurs in gluconeogenesis but not in glycolysis?","answers":[{"option":"Conversion of fructose-6-phosphate to fructose-1,6-bisphosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Conversion of dihydroxyacetone to glyceraldehyde-3-phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Conversion of fumarate into malate","bool":false},{"option":"Conversion of glucose to glucose-6-phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Conversion of pyruvate to phosphoenolpyruvate","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A 40-year-old man is admitted to a local hospital. He has a 102°F temperature along with abdominal pain. His skin color is pale and he has diarrhea. His liver enzymes are in high ranges. Which liver enzyme may be elevated in his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Lactate carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate kinase","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine kinase","bool":false},{"option":"Alanine aminotransferase","bool":true},{"option":"Aspartate dehydrogenase","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"During electron transport, a pair of electrons is accepted from NADH by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"NADH-coenzyme Q reductase","bool":true},{"option":"Cytochrome c oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Succinate-coenzyme Q reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Coenzyme Q-succinate reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Coenzyme Q-cytochrome c reductase","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Chemosmotic theory for oxidative phosphorylation proposes ATP generation via which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Glycolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-oxidation","bool":false},{"option":"NADH+ transport","bool":false},{"option":"Proton gradient","bool":true},{"option":"Ca+ concentration","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is an enzyme of the glycolysis pathway that is activated due to low levels of cellular ATP?","answers":[{"option":"Isomerase","bool":false},{"option":"Pyruvate kinase","bool":false},{"option":"Hexokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphofructokinase","bool":true},{"option":"Glucokinase","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Where are the enzymes of the tricarboxylic acid (TCA cycle) in a eukaryotic cell located?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Lysosomal bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondria","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A 35-year-old female patient comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of abdominal pain, dark urine, itchy skin, and fatigue. Her labs show total bilirubin 8.5 mg/dl (0.1-1. mg/dl), SGOT 99 U/L (40-129 U/L), SGPT 39 U/L (8-48 U/L), alkaline phosphatase 305 U/L (40-129 U/L) and gamma GT 166 U/L (8-61 U/L). Which of the following is this patient suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Hemolytic jaundice","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis B infection","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive jaundice","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatic jaundice","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocellular carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Hepatic encephalopathy is due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Accumulation of colonic bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Accumulation of glutamine and glutamate","bool":true},{"option":"Accumulation of urea in brain tissues","bool":false},{"option":"Extensive muscle degradation","bool":false},{"option":"Excessive metabolism of dietary protein","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Digestion of which one of the following does not begin in the mouth?","answers":[{"option":"Amylopectin","bool":false},{"option":"Complex carbohydrates","bool":false},{"option":"Amylose","bool":false},{"option":"Proteins","bool":true},{"option":"Lipids","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Storage of vitamin B12 is one of the functions of the liver related to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Blood formation","bool":true},{"option":"Synthesis of plasma proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Deamination of amino acids","bool":false},{"option":"Detoxification of various substances","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following metabolic pathways maintain blood glucose concentration during fasting?","answers":[{"option":"Liver glycogenolysis","bool":true},{"option":"Erythrocyte glycolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Muscles glycogenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Hexose monophosphate shunt (HMS)","bool":false},{"option":"Tricarboxylic acid (TCA) cycle","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"While assessing obesity in women, an android type is defined by which of the following waist-to-hip ratio?","answers":[{"option":"Less than 0.8","bool":false},{"option":"More than 0.8","bool":true},{"option":"Less than 1","bool":false},{"option":"Equal to 1","bool":false},{"option":"More than 1","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Upper body obesity is linked with higher health risks because of which of the following characteristics of adipose deposits?","answers":[{"option":"Anatomically close to heart","bool":false},{"option":"Utilized for energy","bool":false},{"option":"Deposited in muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Release free fatty acids into portal vein","bool":true},{"option":"Encapsulate liver","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following changes occur in fat cells during voluntary weight loss?","answers":[{"option":"Number is not affected","bool":true},{"option":"Reaccumulates fat","bool":false},{"option":"Programmed cell death","bool":false},{"option":"Size is not reduced","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is a chemical factor released from the stomach that influences food intake and physical activity?","answers":[{"option":"Leptin","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Ghrelin","bool":true}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A 40-year-old woman has had increasing abdominal girth for a month, and pain for the past few days. On physical examination, there is hepatomegaly and caput medusae. Laboratory studies show hemoglobin 20.5 g/dL, hematocrit 61.7%, platelet count 411,000/mm3, aspartate transaminase (AST) 333 U/L, and alanine transaminase (ALT) 358 U/L. What is ultrasonography of her abdomen most likely to show?","answers":[{"option":"Macrovesicular steatosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocellular carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic vein thrombosis","bool":true},{"option":"Choledocholithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Cirrhosis","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Barrett esophagus is a serious, long-term complication of chronic gastroesophageal reflux. Which of the following conditions is diagnostic for Barrett esophagus?","answers":[{"option":"Gastric gland metaplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Intestinal dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous metaplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Intestinal metaplasia","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is true regarding hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection?","answers":[{"option":"Viral RNA disappears when anti-HCV appears in the blood","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-HCV antibody is protective against subsequent infections","bool":false},{"option":"Increased levels of anti-HCV antibodies confer effective immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Episodic elevations of serum aminotransferase levels","bool":true},{"option":"Being an RNA virus, vertical transmission is not possible","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following conditions is true regarding the presence of antibodies against hepatitis B surface antigen in blood?","answers":[{"option":"Indicates a complete recovery or immunity","bool":true},{"option":"It is detectable after HBsAg disappears","bool":false},{"option":"Indicates immunity after inoculation with HBV vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Indicates current or previous infection","bool":false},{"option":"Helps to distinguish acute from chronic infection","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A 45-year-old man with long-standing gastroesophageal reflux undergoes upper gastrointestinal endoscopy that reveals patchy areas of epithelium resembling gastric mucosa extending 5 cm proximal to the esophagogastric junction. Biopsies are obtained. The pathological report describes \"Barrett esophagus\". Which of the following processes does this finding represent?","answers":[{"option":"Metaplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoma in situ","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Atrophy","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"What is the cause of nonspecific bacterial sialadenitis, frequently involving submandibular glands?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus salivarius","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus saprophyticus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus mutans","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"What is the most common tumor of the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Pleomorphic adenoma","bool":true},{"option":"Warthin tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoid cystic carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Oncocytoma","bool":false},{"option":"Basal cell adenoma","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"The biopsy specimen taken from the stomach shows a superficial mucosal defect and mucosal neutrophilic infiltrate. Which term best describes the features?","answers":[{"option":"Peptic ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric erosion","bool":false},{"option":"Acute gastritis","bool":true},{"option":"Hemorrhagic gastritis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic gastritis","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which one of the following is unlikely to be the morphological feature of Helicobacter\r\npylori gastritis?","answers":[{"option":"Present as antral gastritis","bool":false},{"option":"Increased parietal cell mass and acid secretion","bool":true},{"option":"Mucosal atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Increased risk of adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Intestinal metaplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which one of the following is a reversible hepatic response to injury?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatocyte necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrosis (stellate cells)","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocyte apoptosis","bool":false},{"option":"Cholestasis","bool":true},{"option":"Cirrhosis","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"What is the doctor's ability to understand another person's culture, demonstrate knowledge of it and accept and respect the difference between his/her culture and clients' known as?","answers":[{"option":"Cultural difference","bool":false},{"option":"Cultural awareness","bool":false},{"option":"Cultural competence","bool":true},{"option":"Cultural motivation","bool":false},{"option":"Cultural sensitivity","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is a structure involved in the formation of the stomach bed?","answers":[{"option":"Duodenojejunal flexure","bool":false},{"option":"Right kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse mesocolon","bool":true},{"option":"Right dome of diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Right adrenal gland","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following neurohormones/neurotransmitters stimulate gastric acid secretion?","answers":[{"option":"Histamine","bool":true},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamine","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Vagally mediated increase in gastric acid secretion is partially mediated by which of the\r\nfollowing?","answers":[{"option":"Gastrin releasing peptide (GRP)","bool":true},{"option":"Gastric inhibitory peptide (GIP)","bool":false},{"option":"Atropine","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoactive intestinal polypeptide (VIP)","bool":false},{"option":"Somatostatin","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"HCI is part of gastric secretion but its excessive secretion may lead to peptic ulcer. Hydrogen ion secretion by parietal cells occurs through which of the following pumps?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrogen-calcium ATPase","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen-chloride ATPase","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium-hydrogen ATPase","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium-potassium ATPase","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen-potassium ATPase","bool":true}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following artery supplies blood to the lesser curvature of the stomach?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior gastric","bool":false},{"option":"Right gastro-omental","bool":false},{"option":"Short gastric","bool":false},{"option":"Gastroduodenal","bool":false},{"option":"Left gastric","bool":true}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following artery is most likely to be eroded by an ulcer in the lesser curvature of the stomach?","answers":[{"option":"Short gastric","bool":false},{"option":"Gastroduodenol","bool":false},{"option":"Splenic","bool":false},{"option":"Left gastric","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior pancreaticodudenol","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following cells are present in the glands of the normal mucosa of the stomach?","answers":[{"option":"Parietal","bool":true},{"option":"Enterocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Paneth","bool":false},{"option":"Absorptive","bool":false},{"option":"M cells","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"The pain in the epigastric region in peptic ulcer disease is referred through which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Lesser splanchnic","bool":false},{"option":"Greater splanchnic","bool":true},{"option":"Lower intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Gray rami communicans","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"In a research paper, the following line is written: \"To assess the frequency of mood disorders among medical students of Karachi.\" Which one of the following options best describes the statement in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Hypothesis","bool":false},{"option":"Topic","bool":false},{"option":"Objective","bool":true},{"option":"Operational definitions","bool":false},{"option":"Rationale","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A group of medical students submits the plan for their research project to the institutional board. This plan contains background, objectives, hypothesis, methodology, consent form, questionnaire, and references. Which one of the following options best defines this plan for research in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Introduction","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothesis","bool":false},{"option":"Abstract","bool":false},{"option":"Rationale","bool":false},{"option":"Synopsis","bool":true}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"In a small study, 12 women with endometrial cancer and 12 women with no apparent disease are contacted and asked whether they have ever used estrogen. Each woman with cancer is matched by age, race, weight, and parity to a woman without the disease. Which one of the following options best describes the type of study design in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Cross-sectional","bool":false},{"option":"Case-control","bool":true},{"option":"Cohort","bool":false},{"option":"Ecological","bool":false},{"option":"Case report","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"In a clinical trial, neither participants nor investigator is aware of the group allocation and treatment received. Which one of the following options best describes the type of\r\nblinding in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Triple blinding","bool":false},{"option":"Double blinding","bool":true},{"option":"Single blinding","bool":false},{"option":"Masking","bool":false},{"option":"No blinding","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following increases gastric acid secretion?","answers":[{"option":"Duodenal alkalinity","bool":true},{"option":"Gastric acidity","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal acidity","bool":false},{"option":"H2 receptor antagonists","bool":false},{"option":"Vagotomy","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"The appendicular artery is a branch of which of the following arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Iliocolic artery","bool":true},{"option":"Right colic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cecal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left colic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle colic artery","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following cells are present in the small intestinal epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Teniae coli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Chief cells","bool":false},{"option":"Mucous neck cells","bool":false},{"option":"Oxyntic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Paneth cells","bool":true}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Cremasteric muscle is supplied by which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Iliohypogastric nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Subcostal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ilioinguinal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Genital branch of genitofemoral","bool":true},{"option":"Femoral nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A histologist was looking at the slide of a gastrointestinal organ. The mucosa of the organ showed a number us folds with not-so-deep pits. The muscularis externa had three layers, inner oblique, middle circular, and outer longitudinal. Which organ can it be?","answers":[{"option":"Gallbladder","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":true},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenum","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Amino acids that are converted to acetyl-CoA cannot be used for gluconeogenesis because acetyl-coA cannot be converted to pyruvate. Which amino acids are these?","answers":[{"option":"Ketogenic","bool":true},{"option":"Semi-essential","bool":false},{"option":"Non-essential","bool":false},{"option":"Essential","bool":false},{"option":"Glucogenic","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A 53-year-old male came to the emergency department due to marked hematemesis for the last three hours. On examination, he had a distended abdomen and fluid wave. What is the patient likely suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Massive hepatic necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"HAV infection","bool":false},{"option":"Cholangiocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cirrhosis","bool":true},{"option":"Fatty liver","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is a distinguishing feature of the gallbladder?","answers":[{"option":"Thick muscularis","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"No submucosa","bool":true},{"option":"Simple cuboidal epithelium in mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Thick submucosa","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the first identified case in a location?","answers":[{"option":"Tertiary case","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial case","bool":false},{"option":"Index case","bool":true},{"option":"Secondary case","bool":false},{"option":"Primary case","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which hormone increases pancreatic enzymatic secretion, decreases gastric emptying, and is secreted due to the presence of fatty acids and protein breakdown products in the duodenum?","answers":[{"option":"Gastrin","bool":false},{"option":"Somatostatin","bool":false},{"option":"Motilin","bool":false},{"option":"Secretin","bool":false},{"option":"Cholecystokinin","bool":true}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Acetyl-CoA is used in the synthesis of cholesterol. Which of the following is the rate-limiting step for cholesterol synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Synthesis of farnesyl","bool":false},{"option":"Synthesis of mevalonate","bool":true},{"option":"Synthesis of HMG-CoA","bool":false},{"option":"Synthesis of squalene","bool":false},{"option":"Synthesis of isopentenyl pyrophosphate (IPP)","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A 40-year-old male patient visits the outpatient department with complaints of epigastric pain. The pain is relieved by meals and antacids. Gastric analysis shows increased basal and active acid secretion. Which of the following causes gastric hypersecretion?","answers":[{"option":"Vasoactive intestinal peptide","bool":false},{"option":"Secretin","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrin","bool":true},{"option":"Somatostatin","bool":false},{"option":"Enterogastrone","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"During the early stages of fasting, what maintains a steady level of glucose after dietary glucose runs out?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatic glycogenolysis","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatic fatty acid oxidation","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic ketogenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic glycolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic gluconeogenesis","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"MMA fighter got punched in the abdomen and injured his rectus abdominis muscle. Which of the following nerves supply this muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Lowest thoracic","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Lower six thoracic","bool":true},{"option":"Upper six thoracic","bool":false},{"option":"Ilioinguinal","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following structures forms the left boundary of the lesser sac when viewing a transverse section image of the peritoneal cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Omental foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Splenorenal ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Lesser omentum","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Left kidney","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following are present in the space of Disse?","answers":[{"option":"Cholangiocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Kupffer cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic veins","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic stellate cells","bool":true}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which of the following is true for marasmus?","answers":[{"option":"Too much edema","bool":false},{"option":"Malnutrition but no anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of protein more than calorie","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of calorie more than protein","bool":true},{"option":"Excessive body weight","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"The hepatic artery proper is a branch of the common hepatic artery. Which of the following structures does it pass through before entering the liver?","answers":[{"option":"Splenorenal ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatophrenic ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatoduodenal ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatogastric ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrosplenic ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"The coronary ligament attaches the liver to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"First part of duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Left suprarenal gland","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse colon","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":true}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"In which part of the gastrointestinal tract is most of the vitamin b12 is absorbed?","answers":[{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"Ileum","bool":true},{"option":"Jejunum","bool":false},{"option":"Colon","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"How does the rectum differ from the descending colon histologically?","answers":[{"option":"It lacks payers patches","bool":false},{"option":"It has a comparatively smooth muscularis externa","bool":true},{"option":"It has no submucosa","bool":false},{"option":"It is completely covered by adventitia","bool":false},{"option":"It has no muscularis mucosa","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Gallbladder releases its secretion in a structure present between its neck and the cystic duct. Which of the following structures matches this description?","answers":[{"option":"Major duodenal papilla","bool":false},{"option":"Hartman's pouch","bool":true},{"option":"Body of stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Common hepatic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Fundus","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"A small triangular muscle is located anterior to the lower part of the rectus abdominis muscle within the rectus sheath and attached to the pubic symphysis and the pubic crest. It tenses the linea alba and is often absent in some people. Which of the following muscles matches this description?","answers":[{"option":"External oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Psoas","bool":false},{"option":"Internal oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Transversalis facia","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidalis","bool":true}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"The posterior boundary of the omental foramen or foramen of Winslow is formed by which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Peritoneum of duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"Peritoneum of hepatoduodenal ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Peritoneum of inferior vena cava","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatic portal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Peritoneum of liver","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Considering its origin at the pubic crest, pubic tubercle, and pubic symphysis, and its insertion on the costal cartilages, at which level of the ribs does the rectus abdominis muscle insert?","answers":[{"option":"VIII-X","bool":false},{"option":"V-VII","bool":true},{"option":"VII-IX","bool":false},{"option":"V-XI","bool":false},{"option":"V-IX","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"During inflammation which of the following chemicals are responsible for causing pain?","answers":[{"option":"Interleukins and tumor necrosis factor","bool":false},{"option":"Bradykinin and prostaglandins","bool":true},{"option":"Histamine and serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Nitric oxide and leukotrienes","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine and dopamine","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Gallbladder pain is referred to the right infrascapsular region. It receives its innervation from which nerve roots?","answers":[{"option":"C3-C5","bool":true},{"option":"T12-L2","bool":false},{"option":"T11-L1","bool":false},{"option":"T7-T9","bool":false},{"option":"L1-S2","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2022","question":"Which germ layer gives rise to muscularis externa of the gut?","answers":[{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Ectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Neural crest cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neural tube","bool":false}]}]
export default arr